Guide to the Adolph M. Foerster Collection, 1868-1923 CAM.FOER.2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Music Manuscripts, I.
  - Opus 59 At twilight (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 3rd trombone (Box 11, Item 160s)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: tenor sax (Box 11, Item 160t)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: alto sax (Box 11, Item 160u)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: baritone sax (Box 11, Item 160v)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st and 2nd baritone (Box 11, Item 160w)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: flugal horn (Box 11, Item 160x)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 1st bass (Box 11, Item 160y)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: 2nd bass (Box 11, Item 160z)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: tympani (Box 11, Item 160aa)
    - Opus 59 At twilight: G.fro.beck (Box 11, Item 160bb)
  - Opus 61 Serenade-trio, May 1904 (Box 11, Folder 162)
    Holograph score. Violin, violincello, and piano. On the inside cover in pencil it is marked as the first version.
  - Opus 61 Serenade-trio (Box 11, Folder 163)
    Holograph score. Violin, violincello, and piano. Note on cover that this is the second version.: Includes page fragment at the end of the score.
  - Opus 61 Serenade-trio (Box 11, Folder 164)
    Holograph score. Piano, violin, and violincello. This appears to be the copy sent to the printers and the published version agrees in every respect.
  - Opus 62 no. 1 Prelude in F minor. In Memoriam (Box 11, Folder 166)
    Holograph score. Organ.
  - Opus 62 no. 3 Prelude in E minor (Box 11, Folder 167)
    Holograph score. Organ. page 4 is made up like a title page and lists the numbers.
  - Opus 62 no. 3 Postlude in e minor (Box 11, Folder 168)
    Holograph score. The first 24 measures are the same as item 167 but from there on it is totally different. The opus number is crossed out so it is assumed that Foerster discarded the postlude in favor of another prelude.
  - Opus 64 no. 9 Heart Song; Opus 64 no. 10; Love aloneWaltz; Captain Jinks (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - Opus 64 no. 9 Heart Song, August 14, 1906 (Box 11, Item 170a)
      Holograph score. pencil sketch.
    - Opus 64 no. 10 Love alone (Box 11, Item 170b)
      Voice and piano holograph score. pencil sketch.
    - Waltz, 1860 (Box 11, Item 170c)
      Holograph score. dated 1860 and listed as opus 2 but it was probably a student work.
    - Captain Jinks (Box 11, Item 170d)
      Holograph piano score. also an early work, but without an opus number assigned. The last two works are on the front and back side of the score which is stitched together with thread.
  - Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby; Opus 72 no. 2 A blight has fallen; Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby, September 1, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 174.1)
      Holograph score and parts. String orchestra.
      - Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby: cello, September 1, 1912 (Box 11, Item 174.1a)
      - Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby: violin, September 1, 1912 (Box 11, Item 174.1b)
    - Opus 72 no. 2 A blight has fallen, September 1, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 174.2)
      - Opus 72 no. 2 A blight has fallen: score (Box 11, Item 174.2a)
      - Opus 72 no. 2 A blight has fallen: cello (Box 11, Item 174.2b)
      - Opus 72 no. 2 A blight has fallen: violin (Box 11, Item 174.2c)
    - Opus 64 no. 4 The robin's lullaby (Box 11, Item 174.3)
      Holograph score. String orchestra. Also one page of score which probably belongs to this group.
  - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany (Box 11, Folder 176)
    Holograph score and parts. Many parts have previous versions crossed out on reverse side.
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: score (Box 11, Item 176a)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: 1st violin (Box 11, Item 176b)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: 2nd violin (Box 11, Item 176c)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: viola (Box 11, Item 176d)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: cello (Box 11, Item 176e)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: bass (Box 11, Item 176f)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: flute (Box 11, Item 176g)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: oboe (Box 11, Item 176h)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: clarinet (Box 11, Item 176i)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: bassoon (Box 11, Item 176j)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 11, Item 176k)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: trumpet (Box 11, Item 176l)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: trombone (Box 11, Item 176m)
    - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany: violin (Box 11, Item 176n)
  - Opus 65 no. 3 Love's litany, October 19, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 177)
    Holograph manuscript. Voice and orchestra. Early ink copy with many corrections.
  - Opus 68 no. 1 Sunday in May (Box 11, Folder 178)
    Holograph score. male chorus. pencil sketch
  - Opus 72 Two songs, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 185)
    Holograph manuscript. Voice and piano. 1. Enslaved (Hepp) 2. A blight has fallen (Hepp)
  - Opus 74 no. 1 The Indian maid (Box 12, Folder 187)
    Holograph score. Voice and piano
  - Opus 78 no. 1 Song of hope, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    Holograph score. incomplete
  - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano (Box 12, Folder 194)
    Holograph manuscript. Contains parts 1, 2, and 3
    - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano: score (Box 12, Folder 194a)
    - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano: violin (Box 12, Item 194b)
  - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano (Box 12, Folder 195)
    Holograph score. Incomplete. Begins with the last few measures of the interludium and contains all of the finale.
  - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano: score (Box 12, Item 196a)
    - Opus 79 Suite for violin and piano: violin (Box 12, Item 196b)
  - Opus 80 Love visions, May 1, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 197)
  - Opus 80 Love visions, May 1, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Opus 80 Love visions, May 1, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    Holograph score. Voice and piano. Pages bound with gamble hinge.
  - Opus 80 Love visions, May 1, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 200)
    Holograph score. Voice and piano. Printer's copy.
  - Opus 80 Love visions (Box 12, Folder 201)
    Holograph score. voice, orchestra and 1st violin
    - Opus 80 Love visions: score (Box 12, Item 201a)
    - Opus 80 Love visions: violin (Box 12, Item 201b)
    - Opus 80 Love visions: voice (Box 12, Item 201c)
  - Opus 81 America ode, June 22, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 204)
    Holograph Orchestra score. Inside cover page has first performance on September 23, 1913, at the Pittsburg exposition, Russian symphony orchestra under Modeste Altschuler.
  - Opus 82 no. 1 Autumn wanderings (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - Opus 82 Lyric suite (Box 13, Folder 207)
    Holograph piano score. 2. Air for g string 3. Berceuse
  - Opus 82 no. 4 Spring wanderings (Box 13, Folder 208)
    Holograph score. pencil sketch: The reverse of each page includes other parts copied in Gus Mueller's hand (includes cello part): Each verso is scanned immediately following the corresponding recto)
  - Opus 82 Lyric suite (Box 13, Folder 209)
    String orchestra holograph score and parts. 2. Air for g string 4. Spring wandering
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: score (Box 13, Item 209a)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 1st violin (Box 13, Item 209b)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 2nd violin (Box 13, Item 209c)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: viola (Box 13, Item 209d)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: cello (Box 13, Item 209e)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: bass (Box 13, Item 209f)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: triangle (Box 13, Item 209g)
  - Opus 82 Lyric suite (Box 13, Folder 210)
    String orchestra holograph score. 1. Autumn wanderings 2. Air for the g string 3. Berceuse part 4 not included.
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: score (Box 13, Item 210a)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 1st violin (Box 13, Item 210b)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: viola (Box 13, Item 210c)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 2nd violin (Box 13, Item 210d)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: cello (Box 13, Item 210e)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: bass (Box 13, Item 210f)
  - Opus 82 Lyric suite (Box 13, Folder 211)
    string orchestra score and holograph parts. Part 4 omitted and other three parts in irregular order.: Incomplete
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: score (Box 13, Item 211a)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 1st violin (Box 13, Item 211b)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: 2nd violin (Box 13, Item 211c)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: viola (Box 13, Item 211d)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: cello (Box 13, Item 211e)
    - Opus 82 Lyric suite: bass (Box 13, Item 211f)
  - Opus 83 Trio in d for violin, violoncello and piano (Box 13, Folder 212)
    Holograph score. 1. Trio 2. Intermezzo 3. Finale. This is probably the first sketch for there are different size sheets inserted and several pages which can not be matched with the string parts. The string parts are in ink and bound in orange linen covers with gamble hinge. Also one double score page in ink which matches the parts but is crossed out.: Note messages scanned into the score (these pages are scanned twiced, once with the message, once without)
    - Opus 83 Trio in d for violin, violoncello and piano: score (Box 13, Item 212a)
    - Opus 83 Trio in d for violin, violoncello and piano: violin (Box 13, Item 212b)
    - Opus 83 Trio in d for violin, violoncello and piano: cello (Box 13, Item 212c)
  - Opus 84 no. 2 Maypole dance (sic., i.e. no. 1) (Box 13, Folder 213)
    piano holograph score.
  - Opus 84 no. 2 Homage to Mozart and Opus 39 no. 1 Cavatine, November 3, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - Opus 84 no. 2 Homage to Mozart (Box 13, Item 214a)
      Pencil sketch. The last twelve measures are not included.
    - Opus 39 no. 1 Cavatine (Box 13, Item 214b)
  - Opus 84 no. 2 Homage to Mozart, November 3, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - Opus 85 Enchanter's dream waltz, October 26, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 217)
    holograph piano score. piano sketch.: Includes sketch of different material in Gus Mueller's hand on the verso of each leaf.
  - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream (Box 13, Folder 218)
    String orchestra. Holograph score. Pencil sketch
  - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream (Box 13, Folder 219)
    string orchestra holograph score.
  - Opus 85 The Enchanter's Dream (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: 2nd violin (Box 13, Item 220b)
    - Opus 85 The Enchanter's dream: 1st violin (Box 13, Folder 220a)
      holograph score. String orchestra.
  - Opus 86 Legend and Opus 36 no. 1 Novelette (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Opus 86 Legend (Box 13, Item 222a)
      Pencil sketch. Holograph piano score.
    - Opus 36 no. 1 Novelette (Box 13, Item 222b)
      Violin and piano holograph score. Incomplete.
  - Opus 86 Legend (Box 13, Folder 223)
    Holograph piano score. This sketch has indications of orchestration ahead. Pencil.
  - Opus 86 A legend, part 2 (Box 13, Folder 224)
    Holograph piano score. Pencil sketch.: Includes sketching over a cello part from "Fest-Marsch"
  - Opus 51 Verzweiflung; A Bedouin Love song; Tis all for thee (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Opus 51 Verzweiflung, December 34, 1895 (Box 14, Item 228a)
    - A Bedouin love song, January 19, 1920 (Box 14, Item 228b)
      voice and piano. holograph score.
    - Tis all for thee, May 8, 1918 (Box 14, Item 228c)
  - A Bedouin love song, Jan. 20, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 229)
  - Tis all for thee (Box 14, Folder 230)
    Voice and piano. Holograph score.
  - Tis all for thee, May 8, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 231)
  - For the 2000th organ recital, May 30, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 232)
  - Postlude in d minor, Oct. 4, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - Autumn moods (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - Autumn Moods: 1st violin (Box 14, Item 234a)
    - Autumn Moods: 2nd violin (Box 14, Item 234b)
  - Pastorale, March 8, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 235)
    Holograph organ score. This score has some markings for possible orchestration. There are many corrections.
  - Pastorale (Box 14, Folder 236)
    Holograph organ score.
  - Pastorale (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - [untitled] Organ work in d (Box 14, Folder 238)
    Holograph organ score. Foerster uses the letters C. and H. for Charles Heinroth whose name appears on the first page.
  - A joke for Robert, July 19, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 239)
    Holograph piano score. Outside pages have string parts from another work.
  - Heroic march for piano, Jan. 17, 1905 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Merry Christmas (Box 14, Folder 241)
    Holograph piano score. Pencil sketch.
  - Merry Christmas (Box 14, Folder 242)
    Holograph piano score.
  - Rondo for the piano (Box 14, Folder 243)
    Holograph score. Piano sketch.
  - The merry hunters, March 18, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - The jolly hunters (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Festal prelude (Box 14, Folder 246)
    Holograph piano score. themes found on A.C. (Andrew Carnegie)
  - Festal Prelude (Box 14, Folder 247)
    Holograph piano score. founded on the letters A.C. (Andrew Carnegie).
  - If in loving, singing (Box 14, Folder 248)
    Holograph score. voice, violin obbligato and piano. pencil sketch.
  - If in loving, singing (Box 14, Folder 249)
    Holograph score. voice, violin obbligato and piano. expanded and more complete version of item 248.
  - At the spinning wheel (Box 14, Folder 250)
    voice and piano holograph score.
  - Song of praise and Come o'er the sea (Box 14, Folder 251)
    Voice and piano holograph. Pencil sketch.
    - Song of Praise (Box 14, Item 251a)
    - Come o'er the Sea (Box 14, Item 251b)
  - If in loving, singing, Feb. 10, 1910 (Box 14, Folder 252)
    Voice and piano. Holograph score. Not the same item as 248.
  - With bees and fawn, a child's song (Box 14, Folder 253)
    Holograph score. Pencil sketch, incomplete.
  - Love's victory, December 18, 1908 (Box 14, Folder 254)
    Voice and piano holograph score.
  - My harp (Box 14, Folder 255)
    Holograph voice and piano score. Incomplete. The voice part is written out but the piano part is only indicated in part.
  - Sail on, March 8, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 256)
  - Sail on, June 13, 1908 (Box 14, Folder 257)
  - Sail on and Hero and Leander (Box 14, Folder 258)
    - Sail on (Box 14, Item 258a)
    - Hero and Leander (Box 14, Item 258b)
      Holograph score. This is not the same as opus 44 but has a text by Thomas Moore.
  - Sail on and Hero and Leander (Box 14, Folder 259)
    Holograph voice and piano score.
    - Sail on (Box 14, Item 259a)
    - Hero and Leander (Box 14, Item 259b)
  - Hero and Leander, January 14, 1908 (Box 14, Folder 260)
    voice and piano holograph score. Motto: Hellespont I.
  - Hero and Leander, January 14, 1908 (Box 14, Folder 261)
    Holograph score, voice and piano. Motto: Abyoos. This item is the same as 260.
  - The flower of love and My dream (Box 14, Folder 262)
    - The flower of love, February 19, 1893 (Box 14, Item 262a)
    - My Dream, February 6, 1893 (Box 14, Item 262b)
  - If with all your heart (Box 14, Folder 263)
  - Fruhling, June 10, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 264)
    Voice and piano holograph score. pencil sketch, piano part not filled out.
  - Tuscan rosa, July 19, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 265)
  - To sit beside a crystal spring (Box 14, Folder 266)
  - Hush, hush, Feb. 12, 1912 (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Song to May, December 15, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - Another year hath fled (Box 14, Folder 269)
  - Friend after friend departs, January 12, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 270)
  - Nymph of the wood, July 11, 1890 (Box 14, Folder 271)
  - The hawthorne tree, Nov. 29, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 272)
  - Sing to the Lord (Box 14, Folder 274)
    For anthem choir. Holograph score.
  - Georgian boat song, July 21, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 275)
    Mixed chorus holograph score.
  - Psalm 99 and Psalm 100 (Box 14, Folder 276)
    - Psalm 99 (Box 14, Item 276a)
      Chorus holograph score.
    - Psalm 100 (Box 14, Item 276b)
  - Sing to the Lord (Box 14, Folder 277)
  - The resurrection, April 1905 (Box 14, Folder 280)
    Soprano and orchestra holograph score. All parts complete but no words written in for the soprano, just notes. The last ten measures are marked for chorus but still not words.
  - The resurrection, April 1905 (Box 14, Folder 281)
    Soprano and orchestra holograph score. pencil, no text written but the notes are all there.
  - Ave Maria (Box 14, Folder 283)
    Orchestra holograph score. arranged for orchestra by W.F. Hennig.
    - Ave Maria: 1st violin (Box 14, Item 283a)
    - Ave Maria: 2nd violin (Box 14, Item 283b)
    - Ave Maria: viola (Box 14, Item 283c)
    - Ave Maria: cello (Box 14, Item 283d)
    - Ave Maria: bass (Box 14, Item 283e)
    - Ave Maria: cello obligato (Box 14, Item 283f)
    - Ave Maria: flute (Box 14, Item 283g)
    - Ave Maria: 1st and 2nd horn (Box 14, Item 283h)
    - Ave Maria: cornet (Box 14, Item 283i)
    - Ave Maria: trombone (Box 14, Item 283j)
    - Ave Maria: clarinet (Box 14, Item 283k)
  - Romance for strings (Box 14, Folder 284)
  - Reverie (Box 14, Folder 285)
    Holograph orchestra score.
  - Bach, J.S. (Box 14, Folder 286)
    Holograph score and parts. Fuge in es dur fur orchester eingerichtet von Ad. M. Foerster.
    - Bach, J.S.: score (Box 14, Item 286a)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st violin (Box 14, Item 286b)
    - Bach, J.S.: 2nd violin (Box 14, Item 286c)
    - Bach, J.S.: viola (Box 14, Item 286d)
    - Bach, J.S.: cello (Box 14, Item 286e)
    - Bach, J.S.: bass (Box 14, Item 286f)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st flute (Box 14, Item 286g)
    - Bach, J.S.: 2nd flute (Box 14, Item 286h)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st oboe (Box 14, Item 286i)
    - Bach, J.S.: 2nd oboe (Box 14, Item 286j)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st clarinet (Box 14, Item 286k)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st bassoon (Box 14, Item 286l)
    - Bach, J.S.: 1st horn (Box 14, Item 286m)
    - Bach, J.S.: 2nd horn (Box 14, Item 286n)
    - Bach, J.S.: 3rd horn (Box 14, Item 286o)
    - Bach, J.S.: tympani (Box 14, Item 286p)
  - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6 (Box 15, Folder 287)
    Black binder's volume with title on spine containing 10 pieces.
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 86 A legend, nuptial feast (Box 15, Item 287a)
      Holograph orchestra score. Inside cover page has program clipping showing the first performance at Willow Grove Park, Friday, August 5, 1921. Orange linen cover, gamble hinge.:In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 59 At twilight (Box 15, Item 287b)
      Holograph orchestral score. Heavy brown paper cover. Inside cover page has first performance 1903 at the Pittsburg exposition under Walter Damrosch. The poem is by the composer's son, Norman Foerster.:In Binder's Volume Labelede "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 59 At twilight (Box 15, Item 287c)
      Holograph orchestral score. Heavy brown paper cover. Inside cover page has first performance 1903 at the Pittsburg exposition under Walter Damrosch. The poem is by the composer's son, Norman Foerster.:In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 80 Love visions, May 1, 1913 (Box 15, Item 287d)
      Holograph orchestral score. Bound with brown paper cover, on the inside cover page is a poem by the composer and first performance on September 4, 1913, second on August 4, 1923.:In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 69 no. 4 Through the wood (Box 15, Item 287e)
      Voice and orchestra manuscript score. :In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 44 Hero and Leander (Box 15, Item 287f)
      Manuscript voice and orchestra score. First performance listed on inside cover page, November 1, 1897.:In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 82 Lyric suite (Box 15, Item 287g)
      String orchestra manuscript score. bound with heavy green paper and gamble hinge. :In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 81 American ode (Box 15, Item 287h)
      Holograph orchestral score. In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust, March 18, 1898 (Box 15, Item 287i)
      Holograph piano score. In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
    - Foerster Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6: Opus 85 A legend (sic., i.e. Opus 86), July 20, 1914 (Box 15, Item 287j)
      Holograph orchestral score. Bound in orange linen cover, inside cover page has program clipping showing the first performance on August 13, 1920 at Willow Grove Park, Wassili Leps, conductor.:In Binder's Volume Labeled "Foerster's Orchestra MSS Scores Vol. 6"
  - Fragments of piano music (Box 15, Folder 288)
    Holograph score. various sizes.
  - Fragments of vocal music (Box 15, Folder 289)
    Holograph score. Various sizes.
  - Fragments of orchestra music (Box 15, Folder 290)
  - Devotion (Widmung) Op. 39 No. 2 (Box 15, Folder 299)
    Holograph score. wrapper only; inside cover says, vertically, "What a Daisy Told"
  - Unidentified fragment (Box 15, Folder 300)
  - Ave Verum (Box 15, Folder 304)
    Manuscript of Finney's Choral arrangement in Finney's hand; includes typed draft of intro to Volkwein edition and English text of Foerster's lyrics (2 p. )
  - Quartet Op. 33 (Box 16, Folder 310)
    4 parts, each bound in gamble hinge separately.: copied by Gus Mueller
    - Quartet Op. 33: 1st violin (Box 16, Item 310a)
    - Quartet Op. 33: 2nd violin (Box 16, Item 310b)
    - Quartet Op. 33: viola (Box 16, Item 310c)
    - Quartet Op. 33: cello (Box 16, Item 310d)
- Printed Music, II.
  - Opus 3 Andante for the Pianoforte, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Published by Root & Sons Music Co. 6 pages. 10 copies.
  - Opus 6 Sechs Lieder fur eine Singstimme mit Begleitung des Claviers componirt und Robert Franz verehrungsvoll zugeeignet von Adolph M. Foerster (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Opus 7 Nocturne for the Piano, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Philadelphia: Theo. A. Bacher, 1877. 4 copies.
  - Opus 10 Thusnelda (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Leipzig: J. Rieter-Biedermann. plate no. 1138, 2 sets. Characterstuck nach Karl Schafer's gleichnamigen Gedicht fur grosses Orchester: wrapper for parts included with "Kleine Foete" part
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda Piccolo (Box 1, Item 10A)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st flute (Box 1, Item 10B)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd flute (Box 1, Item 10C)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st oboe (Box 1, Item 10D)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd oboe (Box 1, Item 10E)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st clarinet (Box 1, Item 10F)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd clarinet (Box 1, Item 10G)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st bassoon (Box 1, Item 10H)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd bassoon (Box 1, Item 10I)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st horn (Box 1, Item 10J)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd horn (Box 1, Item 10k)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 3rd horn (Box 1, Item 10l)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 4th horn (Box 1, Item 10m)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st trumpet (Box 1, Item 10n)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd trumpet (Box 1, Item 10o)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st trombone (Box 1, Item 10p)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd trombone (Box 1, Item 10q)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 3rd trombone (Box 1, Item 10r)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda tuba (Box 1, Item 10s)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda tympani (Box 1, Item 10t)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 1st violin (Box 1, Item 10u)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda 2nd violin (Box 1, Item 10v)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda viola (Box 1, Item 10w)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda cello (Box 1, Item 10x)
    - Opus 10 Thusnelda bass (Box 1, Item 10y)
  - Opus 12 no. 2 The mists, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    New York: Edward Schuberth & Co., 1882. Voice and piano. plate number 1143
  - Opus 13 Sonnet, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    New York: J.W.V. Prochazka, 1884. 4 pages. Pub. No. 151; The complete sonnet by Petrach beginning, "The eyes, the arms, …" appears on the first page